#### **Eric Simmons**

615-481-3124

Nashville, TN

Ericnrgnash@gmail.com

Github.com/EricEnergy

Linkedin.com/in/ericSimmonsNash

#### SUMMARY

Goal-oriented web developer with strong commitment to collaboration and solutions oriented problem-solving. Use various web design software to develop customer-focused websites and designs. Committed to high standards of web design, user experience and usability for multiple types of endusers. Graphic design background results in judicious, creative, effective websites, apps, and platforms, which propel competitive advantage and revenue growth.

## **EDUCATION**

- Vanderbilt University Coding Boot Camp
- 5 years Leadership in Sales mentoring program.

#### STRENGTHS & PROFESSIONAL SKILL SET

- Ability to work quickly and efficiently with a strong eye for detail
- Marketing and sales management.
- Proven ability to work well under tight deadlines

- Knowledgeable with Microsoft Office Suite and CRM management tools.
- Ability to work with groups and independently

#### CODING, DESIGN AND MISC SKILLS

- HTML, CSS
- Node.js, NPM
- MongoDB
- Photoshop
- Bootstrap/Foundation
- Express
- Jest, Mocha
- Illustrator
- jQuery, AJAX
- MySQL, Sequelize
- Git
- Visual Studio
- JavaScrpit/[ES5,ES6]
- React.js
- Google Suite
- Google Suite

## EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

## **Quality Control Specialist**

Hudson Yards - LSC Communications / Apr 2018 - Oct 2019

- · Assist in developing and maintaining color corrections, retouching and QC standards for all clients
- Responsible for companywide mark-up of in-house content
- Provide color correction, cut-out, banding solution, extension and background replacement services
- Expertise in concept development and realism

## **Account Executive**

Chyron Hego/Click Effects | Jan 2017 - Oct 2018

- Creation and standardization of \$30k \$500k quotes
- Generated sales leads for warranty deals valued between \$8k \$100k
- Responsible for audio sales in all territories resulting in 25% annual sales growth
- Develop new sales strategies for Audio Department while identifying new business prospects
- Manage prospective leads and existing accounts through SalesForce CRM platform

## **Client Relations Specialist**

Click Effects | Jan 2014 - Jan 2017

- Creation and standardization of \$30k \$500k quotes
- Read diagrams and RFPs for current projects to delegate a client's needs
- Generated sales leads through client outreach programs
- Proactive customer support process leading to 98% approval and 84% client return

#### **Logistics Coordinator**

Click Effects | Jan 2011 - Jan 2014

- Read diagrams and RFPs for current projects to delegate a client's needs
- Generated sales leads through client outreach programs
- Serve as the program manager for the implementation of new CRM tool
- Design and implement procedures across workplace to effectively enhance data integrity

Trip Planner App - https://github.com/EricEnergy/tripAssistant\_Project | https://ericenergy.github.io/tripAssistant\_Project/

- This app allows the user to enter a city they are visiting and are given a list of categories of places they can visit, and from the customer selected list, they are shown a list of things to do that then can be saved to their calendar.
- My role was back end functionality, 3<sup>rd</sup> party API integration and miscellaneous task to wrap up the project.
- Tools / languages used: HTML, JavaScript, Node Express, CSS, Bootstrap, OpenWeatherMap API, and OpenTripMap API.

#### Garaged App - https://github.com/EricEnergy/garaged | https://garaged-app.herokuapp.com/

- Garaged was created to be an AirBNB type app but for vehicles. Its purpose is for anyone with extra garage space to make a post in their city, that someone with the lack of space can rent out for a fee.
- My role was back end design with setting up Bcrypt, setting up passports functionality, and as well as a heavy role in the front-end design.
- Tools / languages used: Node Express, Express Handlebars, Sequelize, Passport, BCrypt, CSS, Bootstrap, API Cloudinary, jQuery, Chai, and Jest

# Serv App - https://github.com/EricEnergy/mern-finalproject | https://serv-project.herokuapp.com/

- This app allows the user to enter a city they are visiting and are given a list of categories of places they can visit, and from the customer selected list, they are shown a list of things to do that then can be saved to their calendar.
- My role was back end heavy with 3<sup>rd</sup> party API integration, building routes, build React forms and front end designing.
- Tools / languages used: Mongodb, Express, React, Node, Material-UI, and Cloudinary.